Inventory of the Donald H. Coffeen Photographs, 1885-1965
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Donald H. Coffeen photographs
1885-1965
Coffeen, Donald H.
01764
.10 cubic ft. (1 container)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Photographs of the Sheridan, Wyoming, area.
Biography of Donald H. Coffeen
Donald H. Coffeen was a Sheridan, Wyoming, resident and collector of historical photographs.
Scope and Content
The collection contains copy prints made in 1965 of photographs taken mainly in northern Wyoming between 1885 and 1905. Subjects include the towns of Sheridan and Buffalo, Indians (primarily Crow), and a 1902 recreation of the Battle of the Little Bighorn.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Donald H. Coffeen at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Donald H. Coffeen in 1965.
Access Terms
Crow Indians; Sheridan (Wyo.); Wyoming -- History, 1890-1918
Social Life and Customs; City and Town Life; Native Americans; Photographs; Wyoming
Container List
- Photograph identification list by donor, circa 1965 (Box 1)
- Buffalo, Wyoming:
  - Buffalo, Wyoming, undated (Box 1)
  - Buffalo, Wyoming, 1885 (Box 1)
- Cheyenne Sun Dance:
  - Part of the ceremony of the Cheyenne Sun-Dance, undated (Box 1)
- Crow Indians:
  - Crow Indian beef issue at camp near Crow Agency, Montana, undated (Box 1)
  - Very typical interior of Crow teepee, undated (Box 1)
  - Crow Indian delegation: Two-Belly, Old Crow, Medicine Crow, Long Elk, Plenty Coups, Pretty Eagle, undated (Box 1)
  - Crow girl wearing very fine elk-tooth dress, undated (Box 1)
  - Crow chief with hand drum, undated (Box 1)
- People:
  - Crazy Head - Crow chief: the greatest chief the Crows ever had - that is, he had counted more coups - He is old nearly blind (wearing scalp shirt), undated (Box 1)
  - Curley, in front of his teepee carrying repeater rifle, undated (Box 1)
  - Curley and family, undated (Box 1)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Judge Foster - first settlers in what is now Sheridan County near old Ft. Phil Kearney, undated (Box 1)
  - Edward Gillette on horseback, 1892 (Box 1)
  - Little Bear (Crow story teller) - he could imitate most any bird or animal, undated (Box 1)
  - Medicine Crow (Crow chief), undated (Box 1)
  - Sharp Nose (Arapaho), undated (Box 1)
  - Six Feathers (Arapaho), undated (Box 1)
  - Two Moons (Cheyenne chief) with bear-claw necklace, undated (Box 1)
  - Wolf Lies Down - a very fine example of Indian shirt and war bonnet, undated (Box 1)
- Sheridan, Wyoming, and Sheridan Area:
  - Patrick Stage - Rock Creek to Custer Station, outside Sheridan Inn Stable, 1894 (Box 1)
  - Fourth of July parade on Burkitt St. in Sheridan, undated (Box 1)
  - Placard of William Jennings Bryan in parade for him in Sheridan, circa 1896 (Box 1)
  - Indian travois: these Indians came to Sheridan with their belongings on travois; while some Indians had wagons, those that did not have government issue wagons came with travois, undated (Box 1)
  - Old stage coach on streets of Sheridan for fourth of July parade, circa 1905 (Box 1)
  - Early photo of Sheridan Inn and CB&Q depot, undated (Box 1)
  - Indians performing around Sheridan Inn where Buffalo Bill recruited acts and talent for his Wild West Show, undated (Box 1)
  - Early photo of Sheridan Inn with two of the first automobiles and street car, undated (Box 1)
  - Souvenir Sheridan Inn - Sheridan Wyoming (Coffeen's Indian Rooms, Sheridan, Wyo.), undated (Box 1)
  - Early day picture of Sheridan Brewery, undated (Box 1)
  - The first Dietz coal mine near Sheridan, undated (Box 1)
  - Main Street, Sheridan, Wyoming: horse in front of Coffeen store where Wyo Theater now stands; Wells Fargo offices operated at the site before railroad was built into Sheridan, undated (Box 1)
  - Old steam threshing outfit near Sheridan, undated (Box 1)
  - Coffeen's Indian Rooms - Sheridan; many of these pieces of hand-craft are exceptionally rare and found their way into museums and private collections, circa 1905 (Box 1)
  - Early day picture of Sheridan, dirt street, wagons & teams, no cars, undated (Box 1)
  - Main Street in Sheridan with old Windsor Hotel, many Indian teams hauling oats on a contract to old Ft. Custer in the Big Horn, circa 1890 (Box 1)
  - Steer-roping contest at Sheridan - man is Luther Dunning, circa 1902 (Box 1)
- Tongue River Flume:
  - Tongue River Canyon Flume, undated (Box 1)
- U.S. Military and Indian Wars:
  - General George Crook and Apache scouts (Alchisay and Dutchy) with mule, undated (Box 1)
  - Early picture of Ft. McKinney - Buffalo, Wyo., undated (Box 1)
  - General Brook's camp at Pine Ridge Agency, South Dakota, undated (Box 1)
  - Sham battle of the Custer Battle between Crows and 7th Cavalry, circa 1902 (Box 1)